Guide to the Difficulties Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
The Difficulties Records
1977-1997
YCAL MSS 382
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.52
(11 boxes)
The Difficulties Records contain correspondence, production files, drafts of writings, and printed material relating to the production and publication of journal issues.
Difficulties
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Thomas L. Beckett on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
The Difficulties
The Difficulties was an arts journal started by poet and editor Tom Beckett in 1980. The journal's name was derived from a Charles Olson quote and the journal was published by Viscerally Press in Kent, Ohio. Between 1980 and 1990, six issues were produced, each focusing on process-oriented and language-centered work. The first issue was comprised of responses to a questionnaire about "language environment;" the second was an issue of poetry; and the final four issues were critical considerations of the writers Charles Bernstein, Ron Silliman, David Bromige and Susan Howe.
Scope and Contents
The Difficulties Records contain correspondence, production files, drafts of writings, and printed material relating to the production and publication of journal issues.
Difficulties; American poetry -- 20th Century -- Periodicals; American literature -- 20th Century -- Periodicals; American poetry -- 20th Century -- History and criticism -- Periodicals; Little magazines -- United States; Beckett, Thomas, (Accountant)
- Production files, 1977-1997; 7.52; (11 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by writer and project name.
  - Abacus poetry journals, 1985-1992 (Box 1)
  - Abbot, Steve.Correspondence, newsletters, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Charles. Correspondence, newsletters, brochures, 1991-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Amnasan, Michael. Correspondence, two scripts of "An Unimportant Man", 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - "Anabasis/Thomas Taylor" correspondence about "The Love Project", 1993 (Box 1)
  - "And/Xexoxial" correspondence, 1993 May 8 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Bruce. Correspondence, articles, transcripts of speeches, 1981-1996 (Box 1)
  - Angeline, Mary. Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Antin, David. Correspondence, 1981 Jun 24 (Box 1)
  - Applefield, David. Correspondence, 1985, undated (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Regards Frank Magazine
  - Armantrout, Rae. Correspondence and article "See Armantrout for an Alternate View" by Michael Leddy, 1981, 1994 (Box 1)
  - "(Ohio) Arts Council--Bob Fox" correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Baron, Todd. Correspondence, undated (Box 1)
  - Barone, Dennis. Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 1)
  - "Bayfront NATO--Martin Luther King Ctr" correspondence, brochure, 1987, undated (Box 1)
  - Benedetti, David. Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Benson, Steve. Correspondence, 1981-1994 (Box 1)
  - Berglard, Brita. Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Charles. Correspondence, transcript of an interview with Abigail Child, writings, poetry, "The Sophist", 1980-1994, undated; 4 (Box 1)
  - Berry, Jake. Correspondence, article "Hyperotics: Towards a Theory of Experimental Poetry" by Harry Polkinhorn, responses to "Brambu Drezi", 1995-1996, undated (Box 1)
  - "Bertholf" correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 1)
  - Black Mountain 2 Review. Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - "Magazine blurb file" correspondence, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Boone, Bruce. Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Borneman, Bill. Correspondence, poetry journals, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
  - Bromige, David. Correspondence, writings, newsletters, poetry, assorted proofs of The Difficulties, 1981-1996, undated; 4 (Box 1)
  - Buck, Paul. Correspondence, poetry, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - "Burning Press/L.B. Drake" correspondence, poetry journals, brochures, 1989-1992, undated (Box 1)
  - Burns, Avery. Correspondence, 1996 March12 (Box 1)
  - "Butterick" correspondence, 1979-1987 (Box 1)
  - Byrd, Don. Correspondence, article "Getting Ready to Read 'A''", 1980-1987, undated (Box 1)
  - Byrum, John. Correspondence, poetry journals, writings, newsletters, 1986-1996, undated; 4 (Box 2)
  - "Byrum--Temporary City", undated (Box 2)
  - Callahan, Bob. Correspondence, brochure, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Chadwick, Cydney. Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Chamberlin, Lori. Correspondence, 1987 January 19 (Box 2)
  - Chester, Laura. Correspondence, writing, 1981, undated (Box 2)
  - Chicago Review, correspondence, writings, 1981-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Chriof, David. Correspondence, writings, poetry, photocopies of articles, 1996, undated; 2 (Box 3)
  - "Cincinnati Small Press Fair" certificate, 1988 Oct 15 (Box 3)
  - Coffey, Michael. "Small Press" correspondence, descriptions of books, 1986, undated (Box 3)
  - "Contraflow" correspondence, 1986 July 5 (Box 3)
  - Coolidge, Clark. Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Corman, Cid. Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - "Cory, et. al" correspondence, undated (Box 3)
  - Creeley, Robert. Correspondence, 1981-1988 (Box 3)
  - Dahlen, Bev. Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Dark Ages Clasp the Daisy Root poetry journals, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Davenport, Guy. Correspondence, 1979 November 18 (Box 3)
  - David, Gary. Correspondence, writings, 1980-1995, undated (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Michael. Correspondence, writings, 1980-1981, undated (Box 3)
  - Davies, Alan. Correspondence, writings, poetry, 1980-1994 (Box 3)
  - Davis, Kathe. Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Dawson, Fielding. Correspondence, poetry, draft of The Yellow Cab, and Way #1 " journal, 1981-1996, undated; 3 (Box 3)
  - de Gruttola, Raffael. Correspondence, brochure, 1995, undated (Box 3)
  - DiMichele, William. Correspondence, and draft of "Burnhole", undated (Box 3)
  - DiPalma, Ray. Correspondence, poetry, artwork, 1991-1996, undated (Box 3)
  - "Disturbed Guillotine" correspondence, 1996 (Box 3)
  - DuPlessis, Rachel. Correspondence, 1987-1993, undated (Box 3)
  - Dydo, Ulla. Correspondence, photocopies of pages from The Times Literary Supplement, 1994 (Box 3)
  - "Earwitness" papers pertaining to "EARWITNESS Public Poetry Reading Series", 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Edwards, Ken. Reality Studios correspondence, 1984 May 5 (Box 3)
  - Eigder, Larry. Correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 3)
  - Ellis, Stephen. Correspondence, poetry, photocopies of articles and poetry, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - Fitterman, Rob. Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Foster, Ed. "Talisman" correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
  - Fraser, Kathleen. Correspondence, 1988 November 14 (Box 3)
  - Fredner, Stephen. Correspondence, 1985 May 25 (Box 3)
  - Friedlander, Ben. Correspondence, 1990, undated (Box 3)
  - "The Fund for Poetry" correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - "Furnitures" poetry journals, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Gavick, Pete. Correspondence, poetry journals, writings, 1981-1996 (Box 3)
  - Gansz, David C.D. Correspondence, 1989, undated (Box 3)
  - Glazier, Loss. Correspondence, 1995 May 24 (Box 3)
  - Golding, Alan, Correspondence, photocopies of articles, 1989, undated (Box 3)
  - Gottlieb, Michael. Correspondence, writings, 1993, undated (Box 3)
  - Green, Paul. Correspondence, 1982-1994 (Box 3)
  - Green, Tony. Correspondence, poetry, writings, 1983-1991, undated (Box 3)
  - Gregory, Bob. Correspondence, undated (Box 3)
  - "Grenier" correspondence, poetry journals, photocopies of articles and interview, 1985-1994, undated (Box 4)
  - Grim, Jessica. Correspondence, "Locale" and "It/Ohio" poetry collections, 1991-1997 (Box 4)
  - Gross, Mimi. Postcard, undated (Box 4)
  - "Grossinger" correspondence, photocopy of an article, 1979-1983, undated (Box 4)
  - Hanson, Jeff. Correspondence, 1992-1994, undated (Box 4)
  - Harnik, J.G. Correspondence, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Harrison, Bob. Correspondence, poetry, 1995, undated (Box 4)
  - Harryman, Carla. Correspondence, 1982, 1987 (Box 4)
  - "Hausmann/Disturbed Guillotine" correspondence, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Hejinian, Lyn. Correspondence, 1980-1996 (Box 4)
  - Higgins, Dick. Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Hill, Craig. "Score" correspondence, "American Standard" poetry collection, 1984-1989 (Box 4)
  - Hocquard, Emmanuel. Correspondence, 1990 January 24 (Box 4)
  - Holland, Peter. Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Hollander, Gadi. Correspondence, 1986 July 28 (Box 4)
  - Horvath, Brooks. Correspondence, poetry, photocopies of articles, 1991-1992, undated (Box 5)
  - "House Organ" poetry journals, 1993-1997 (Box 5)
  - Howe, Susan. Correspondence, photocopies of articles, writings, poetry, photographs, issue of The Difficulties, 1979-1989, undated; 2 (Box 5)
  - HOW(ever) poetry journals, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
  - Huth, Geoff. Poetry journals and papers pertaining to them, 1992-1996 (Box 5)
  - Hydock, Jim. "Brief" correspondence, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Intent literary journals, 1989-1991 (Box 5)
  - Interruptions 1 literary journal, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Interruptions 2 literary journal, 1994; 3 (Box 5)
  - Interruptions 3 literary journal, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Irby, Jim. Correspondence, 1979-1985 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Ronald. Correspondence, undated (Box 5)
  - Kaplan, Ed. Correspondence, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Killian, Kevin. Correspondence, 1986-1993 (Box 5)
  - Lansing, Gerrit. Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Leave Books." Juliana Spahr correspondence, 1991-1995, undated (Box 5)
  - Levi Strauss, David. Correspondence, photocopies of articles, copy of Poetry Flash, 1984-1989, undated (Box 5)
  - Levy, Andrew. Correspondence, poem "Song from My Family", 1988-1996 (Box 5)
  - Lewis, Harry. # Magazine correspondence, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Lorenzo, Rafael. Correspondence, photocopies of essay "Fragments of Refusal", 1981-1982, undated (Box 5)
  - Lowell, Douglas. Correspondence, poems, 1985 (Box 5)
  - " Lower Limit Speech " poetry journals/newsletters, 1977-1996, undated (Box 5)
  - Mac Low, Jackson. Correspondence, essay "Charles Bernstein & his Shade", 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - "Mandala" poems, "the MANDALA book", 1978-80 (Box 6)
  - "Mandala--Earl" correspondence, undated (Box 6)
  - Mark, Ezra. Correspondence, 1994 May 13 (Box 6)
  - Marron, John. Correspondence, poems, 1981-1986, undated (Box 6)
  - "S-P Martin" correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 6)
  - Martone, John. Correspondence, 1989 August 31 (Box 6)
  - McPherson, Bruce. Correspondence, 1983 May 6 (Box 6)
  - "Messerli" correspondence, essay "The Rhythms of the 'Language' Poets: A Defense", 1979-1986, undated (Box 6)
  - "Metcalf" correspondence, essays "Incorporation: The Next Frontier" and "Language Environment", 1979-1989, undated (Box 6)
  - Michaelsen, Scott. Correspondence, 1987 Oct 4 (Box 6)
  - Minkoff, George. Correspondence, 1986 (Box 6)
  - "Misc. Proj. Newsletter" poetry journals/ newsletters, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - "Mirage Periodical" correspondence, poetry journals, 1993-1994; 2 (Box 6)
  - Miltner, Robert. Correspondence, 1994 April 27 (Box 6)
  - Motel poetry journals, 1989-1991 (Box 6)
  - Murphy, Sheila E. Correspondence, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Nash, S.S. Correspondence, poetry journal, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Neilson, Melanie. Correspondence, poems, 1990-1996, undated (Box 7)
  - Nelson-Raney, Steve. Correspondence, poems, 1980, undated (Box 7)
  - "B.P. Nichol--Tribute" memorial program, 1988 Dec 2 (Box 7)
  - Nielsen, A.L. Correspondence, poetry collection "Evacuation Routes: A User's Guide," essays, 1981-1990, undated (Box 7)
  - "Ohio Writer" writing newsletters, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
  - "100 Posters Mag" poetry journals, 1977-1981 (Box 7)
  - Ott, Gil. Correspondence, poetry collection "Traffic, Book III," poems, 1980-1991, undated (Box 7)
  - "Ottotole" correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 7)
  - Owen, Maureen. Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Ozment, Kurt. Correspondence, 1987 October 8 (Box 7)
  - "PLGC Newsletter" poetry newsletters, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Padgett, Ron. Correspondence, 1979 November 24 (Box 7)
  - Palmer, Michael. Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 7)
  - "Paradigm Press" correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Paul, Sherman. Correspondence, 1989 Aug 26 (Box 7)
  - Pearson, Ted. Correspondence, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Perelman, Bob. Correspondence, book reviews, essays, poem, 1981-1986, undated (Box 7)
  - Perlman, John. Correspondence, poem, 1980-1991 (Box 7)
  - "Philly Talks" poetry newsletters, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Piombino, Nick. Correspondence, essay, 1981-1994, undated (Box 7)
  - Piper, Paul. Correspondence, poems, undated (Box 7)
  - "Platz" correspondence, poem, 1980 July 16 (Box 7)
  - "Poetic Briefs" poetry criticism, correspondence, 1991-1996, undated (Box 8)
  - "Poetry Center--SF State" correspondence, newsletter, contract, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Pressler, Charlotte. Correspondence, essays, 1991-1994, undated (Box 8)
  - Price, Larry. Correspondence, 1986 January 30 (Box 8)
  - " Primary Writing " poetry journals, 1984-1988 (Box 8)
  - " Qu Magazine " literary journals, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
  - Quartermain, Peter. Correspondence, 1989 August 28 (Box 8)
  - Quasha, George. Correspondence, 1980 February 24 (Box 8)
  - "Raddle Moon/Susan Clark" correspondence, information about "Raddle Moon", 1988-1989, undated (Box 8)
  - Rasula, Jed. "Prospectus for Sulfur's NCR, #20-22", 1987 April 6 (Box 8)
  - Ratcliffe, Stephen. Correspondence, poetry collection "New York Notes", 1983-1993 (Box 8)
  - "Raworth file" correspondence, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Reese, Marshall. Correspondence, 1981 July 16 (Box 8)
  - Reinfeld, Linda. Correspondence, draft of dissertation "Writing as Rescue: Language/Lyric/Poetry", 1987-1989 (Box 8)
  - Retallack, Joan. Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 8)
  - Roberts, Steven. Essays, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Robinson, Kit. Correspondence, poems, poetry journal Abacus, 1981-1989 (Box 8)
  - Rodefer, Steve. Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
  - Royet-Journoud, C. Correspondence, poetry journal Zuk, 1989 (Box 8)
  - "Samperi" correspondence, poems, 1979, undated (Box 8)
  - Scalapino, Leslie. Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 8)
  - Schelling, Andrew. Correspondence, photocopies of letters and articles, 1985-1987, undated (Box 8)
  - Sher, Gaile. Correspondence, "La", 1991 (Box 8)
  - Seaton, Peter. Correspondence, essay, undated (Box 8)
  - "Spencer Selby/Sink" correspondence, list of experimental poetry/art magazines, poems, 1986-1994, undated (Box 8)
  - Selland, Eric. Correspondence, poetry collection "Seven Changes", 1986-1987, undated (Box 8)
  - Sherry, James. Review of "apex of the M, #1," correspondence, essay, 1980-1995, undated (Box 8)
  - Shurin, Aaron. Correspondence, 1983 (Box 8)
  - "Returned Proofs for Silliman" corrected proofs, correspondence, 1983-1984, undated (Box 8)
  - Silliman, Ron. Correspondence, various poetry journals, newspaper, essays, photocopy of poetry collection "Crow", book review, bibliography, "Lit", 1977-1987, undated; 4 (Box 8)
  - Simas, Joey. Correspondence, poetry journal Lamb, poetry journals "Moving Letters," poems, 1980-1987, undated (Box 8)
  - " Situation " poetry journals, 1992, undated (Box 8)
  - " 6ix " poetry journals, 1991-1995 (Box 8)
  - "Smith/Aerial" correspondence, poetry journals, essays, poems, 1985-1993, undated (Box 8)
  - Somerville, Jane. Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Stickney, John. Correspondence, poems, 1988, undated (Box 8)
  - Tabor, Richard. "Lobby Press" correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 8)
  - " TapRoot Review File" correspondence, literature, review journals, reviews, 1992-1996, undated (Box 8)
  - " TapRoot Review File" correspondence, literature, review journals, reviews, 1992-1996, undated (Box 9)
  - Taggart, John. Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
  - Tarachow, M. Correspondence, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Templeton, Fiona. Correspondence, essay, 1989, undated (Box 9)
  - Tills, Stephen E. Correspondence, poem, 1987, undated (Box 9)
  - Tottles Tottel's poetry journals, 1982, undated (Box 9)
  - Townsley, Tom. Correspondence, poems, 1980, undated (Box 9)
  - "Tsunami Editions" correspondence, 1990 September 8 (Box 9)
  - "Tyuonyi/Phillip Foss, Ed." correspondence, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Vartnaw, Bill. Correspondence, poem, 1987 (Box 9)
  - "Versus Project" correspondence, poems, 1988, undated (Box 9)
  - Waldrop, Rosemarie. Correspondence, 1979-1989 (Box 9)
  - Ward, Diane. Correspondence, essay, 1981-1986, undated (Box 9)
  - "Walker/Columbus St. Press" correspondence, poems, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Watson, Craig. Correspondence, poems, essays, "Fear of Performance", 1980-1990, undated; 2 (Box 9)
  - Watten, Barrett. Correspondence, 1981-1985, undated (Box 9)
  - Weinberger, Eliot. "Montemora" correspondence, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Wellman, Don. Correspondence, bylaws and articles of organization of "O.ARS, Inc.", 1981-1987, undated (Box 9)
  - Wellman, John. Correspondence, essay, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
  - "Way #1" poetry collection "Potpourri" by Fielding Dawson, 1995 (Box 10)
  - "Way #2" poetry collection "Three Works" by Sheila E. Murphy, 1996 (Box 10)
  - "Way" poetry collections "Three Works" by Sheila E. Murphy and "'wide streets in double attitude' (1-347)" by Peter Ganick, 1996 (Box 10)
  - "Ganick Way 3" poetry collection "'wide streets in double attitude' (1-347)" by Peter Ganick, 1996 (Box 10)
  - "Amnasan Way 4" play "An Unimportant Man" by Mike Amnasa, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Weiner, Hannah. Correspondence, 1981-1983, undated (Box 10)
  - Westbrook, Brad. Correspondence, photocopies of a children's book, poems, 1990-1991, undated (Box 10)
  - Whelen, Christopher. Correspondence, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Withers, Kenney. "(SI Univ. Press)", 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Woolf, Douglas. Correspondence, 1980 January 2 (Box 10)
  - "Wray" correspondence, photocopies of articles, 1992-1994, undated (Box 10)
  - "Writing Magazine" correspondence, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Young, Geoffrey. Correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 10)
  - Zavatsky, Bill. Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - "Abandoned Interview Anthology Project:" correspondence, notes, interviews, photocopies of articles and interviews, 1986-1988, undated; 4 (Box 10)
  - Unidentified anthology, opening with a piece entitled "Bart", Undated (Box 10)
  - "Name" by Alan ___, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Six issues of The Difficulties and Fielding Dawson chapbook, 1980-1990 (Box 11)